Guide to the International Association of Administrative Professionals, Houston Chapter records, 1948-2003 MS 207
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
International Association of Administrative Professionals, Houston Chapter records
1948-2003
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
International Association of Administrative Professionals. Houston Chapter
MS 207
3 Linear Feet (2 boxes, 1 oversize box)
The collection contains administrative records of the Houston Chapter of the IAAP from its founding in 1948 through 2003. Committee reports, correspondence, scrapbooks, photographs, and newsclippings pertain to the chapter's activities.
Organizational note
The International Association of Administrative Profesionals (IAAP) was founded in 1942 as the National Secretaries Association (NSA). The purpose of the NSA is to improve the standards of the secretarial profession, to provide educational benefits, and to sponsor civic and social activities.
The Houston Chapter of the NSA was chartered on September 28, 1948 at a meeting in the Sam Houston Hotel with 29 charter members. Houston hosted the National Convention for NSA in 1951 at the Shamrock Hotel. The Houston chapter estabilished its first scholarship at the University of Houston for a "worthy high school graduate interested in a secretarial career." The organization changed names in 1981 to Professional Secretaries International and again in 1998 to the International Association of Administrative Professionals (IAAP) to encompass the large number of varied administrative job titles and recognize the advancing role of administrative support staff in business and government.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains administrative records of the Houston Chapter of the IAAP from its founding in 1948 through 2003. Committee reports, correspondence, scrapbooks, photographs, and newsclippings pertain to the chapter's activities. There are also materials from regional and national associations represented in the collection.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Note
Lillian Mayo, President of the Houston Chapter IAAP donated these records in July 2015.
Arrangement
Series I. Houston Chapter Administration and Organization Series II. Scrapbooks and Photographs Series III. Newsclippings and Publications Series IV. Regional and National Associations Series V. Oversize Materials
General
The Houston Chapter's monthly newsletter Strikeovers published 1949-1996 have been catalogued separately and are available in the Woodson Research Center call number: HD8039 .S58 P76.
Index Terms
Subjects
Business; Women
Document Types
newsletters; scrapbooks; annual reports; photographs
- Series I. Houston Chapter Administration and Organization
  - Awards and Certificates (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bylaws, 1958, 1959, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sub-Series I. Committees
    - Committee Chairs, 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Committees Annual Reports, 1949-55 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Committees Annual reports, 1955-58 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Committees Annual reports, 1959-60 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Committees Annual reports, 1960-61 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Committees Annual reports, 1969-70 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Committees Annual reports, 1977-78 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Committees Annual reports, 1978-79 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bulletin Committee, 1988-89 (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
    - Bylaws Committee, 1968-69 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Historian Reports, 1965-66 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Historian Reports, 1966-67 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Historian Reports, 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Historian Reports, 1968-71 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Historian Reports, 1971-75 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Historian Reports, 1976-77 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Historian Reports, 1977-78 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Historian Reports, 1978-79 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Historian Reports, 1979-80 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Historian Reports, 1980-81 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Historian Reports, 1986-97 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Historian Reports, 1998-99 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Membership Committee, 1964-1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Tellers Committee Report, April 1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Sub-Series II. Correspondence
    - 1968-89 (Box 1, Folder 29-31)
  - Sub-Series III. Education
    - CPS Award Dinner, 1967-68, 1970-72 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - CPS Encouragement Programs, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - CPS Examination (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - CPS Incentive Awards (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - CPS Tuition Scholarship Award (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - NSA Education (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Educational Seminars, 1956-2003 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Scholarships (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Sam Houston Endowed Scholarship, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Sub-Series IV. Events
    - Annual Seminar for Secretaries, 1968-73 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Bosses Dinner, 1965, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Executives Recognition Banquet, 1967, 1980, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Introductory remarks, various (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Secretary of the Year (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Sub-Series V. Financial, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Sub-Series VI. History
    - Houston Chapter (bound volume), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Houston Chapter history (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Sub-Series VII. Membership
    - Roster, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Rosters, 1964, 1967-68; Membership.mdb on CD-RW (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Program and Directory, 1962-63, 1963-64 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Membership Data Book Information, 1970-79 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Clarice Sanders (Secretary of the Year 1960) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Honorary Membership, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Honorary Membership, 1956-69 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series VIII. Meeting Minutes
    - Meeting Minutes, 1972, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Board Meeting Reports, 1974, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Meeting Summary, July 16, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series II. Scrapbooks and Photographs
  - Scrapbook boards (Houston Convention, Membership Tea), 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook pages, 1940s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook pages, 1949-1950s (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook pages - Guests (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Scrapbook pages - Chapter Members, 1950-1980s (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook - Elsie McDowell, NSA/CPS, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Series III. Newsclippings and Publications
  - Newsclippings, 1960s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Publications - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - The Secretary, August 1955, June/July 1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Today's Secretary, November 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Parliamentary Journal, July 1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Career Track, Fall 1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - PSI Vision, September 1990, December 1990, March 1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Series IV. Regional and National Associations
  - Future Secretaries Association, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - NSA - Southwestern District Regional Meeting programs, 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - NSA - History of the Southwest District, May 1967 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - NSA - Texas - Louisiana Division Meeting, May 1961 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - IAAP - Texas - Louisiana Division directory, 1988-89 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Texas - Louisiana Division Officers by year, 1952-1984 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Texas-Louisiana Division Ledger, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - NSA Brochure (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - NSA Manual, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - NSA National Convention programs, 1949, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - NSA Secretaries Week, 1963, 1974, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - NSA International Bylaws, Standing Rules and Procedures, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - NSA Minutes of 29th Annual Convention, July 1974 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - NSA Program of the Year, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - PSI Auditors' reports, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - PSI "Now is the Decade of the Professional Secretary" VHS, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - NSA Amendment proposals (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - NSA "A Secretary Credo" (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - NSA Comparison Survey (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - PSI Speakers Bureau (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Series V. Oversize Materials
  - NSA Scrapbook, 1960-61 (Box 3)
  - History of Houston Chapter, 1948-1952 (Box 3)
  - Award of Special Merit, March 19, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Photograph Houston Chapter members pool party, July 9, 1951 (Box 3)